<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Matthew Howell</title>
    <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Matthew Howell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 20:20:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    

    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alt Text</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 20:20:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alt Text&lt;/em&gt; is a small photography and writing project from Matthew Howell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each week, usually on Sunday, a small piece of writing is accompanied by a photograph. The writing focuses on the physical subject of the photo, gently pulling at its larger context, and finding some part of a larger whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work is meant to be something of an inverse of the HTML &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/img&#34;&gt;img&lt;/a&gt; element&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;alt&lt;/em&gt; attribute. In practice, the image&amp;rsquo;s alt text is an accessibility consideration, describing the image, that for any number of reasons may not be viewable by the reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the alt text is offered first, perhaps with more depth and detail than the image itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Positives</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/positives/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 20:20:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/positives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Positives&lt;/em&gt; &lt;mark&gt;was&lt;/mark&gt; a small photography project from Matthew Howell in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each week, a photograph taken with a Polaroid SX-70, on Impossible Project film, scanned in a tiny studio apartment, and shared in the &lt;em&gt;Positives&lt;/em&gt; email newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of these were taken in New York City, but a handful were taken in Thailand, Philadelphia, or other places that I happened to be carrying the camera that year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were 45 photos published in 2014, which are all collected below along with a few unpublished images that were taken for the same project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>