<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alt Text on Matthew Howell</title>
    <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alt Text on Matthew Howell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 20:20:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    

    
    
    <item>
      <title>0006</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0006/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 12:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a tiny international airport on a very small island just off the east coast of Tortola.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On its north end, this airport&amp;rsquo;s single airstrip slices through the tree-covered landscape, pushing across the sand and out into ocean as it becomes part of the shoreline itself, a boundary of concrete and moved earth forming one edge of a small, U-shaped bay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passengers arriving on this very small island can exit the airport terminal, flag a taxi, and take the short car ride over the bridge to the bustling capital city of these islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They can also, if they choose, walk past those waiting cabs and continue east for about a half-mile along the narrow road until they find the shallow beach that wraps around the southern perimeter of that small, U-shaped bay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that beach there are a half-dozen wooden docks that extend out into blue water, as if pointing the way to the awaiting, accidental fleet of idling ships, anchored, gently rocking in place, shielded from the stronger ocean currents by the small peninsula to the east and that runway from the tiny international airport to the west.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those ships will, eventually, return to more open water. The bay unrolls into the greater Atlantic Ocean, dotted with drops of green land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out on that water, from particular angles, the local islands begin to stack on top of one another. The clear horizon, full of peaks and minor elevations that look as if they&amp;rsquo;re part of a larger, connected whole rather than a scattered archipelago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green hills behind green hills behind green hills, water between, but from this vantage, invisible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>0005</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0005/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 12:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0005/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a small train station in Wilmington, Delaware a few blocks away from a community college and a few more from the city&amp;rsquo;s regularly redeveloped waterfront.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The station, a Frank Furness designed, brick and terra cotta building that was completed in 1908, was restored in 2011 and renamed for the then vice president. A man who was well-known, at least locally, for departing on the southbound Acela service every morning and returning home each night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That train station and the tracks that run through it have played an unexpectedly outsized role in my life. Most often, Wilmington served as the southern terminus of my regular Amtrak trips from New York City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visiting family in Delaware meant waiting in Penn Station&amp;rsquo;s crowded concourse, watching the clock, listening for departure announcements, and then descending down the escalator to the tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning home meant waiting in a smaller concourse, watching the clock, listening for departure announcements, and then ascending up the escalator to the tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An email search reveals that, during my seven year residency in the city, I made that trip more than 50 times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The train tickets themselves are a throwback to a simpler world, mostly before ubiquitous computer phones. The earlier trips all depended upon physical paper tickets. Many printed at the FedEx-Kinkos on 80th and Broadway. Some printed on the 15th floor of the an H-shaped financial district skyscraper. Some printed in a harshly lit basement cubicle in Morningside Heights. Some printed on the 5th floor of a SoHo office building, originally built for John Jacob Astor. Some printed in a very forgettable 7th Ave tower with oddly ornate elevators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those tickets were such a corporeal piece of my life that I still occasionally find a paperback Vonnegut novel, pages yellowing, holding on to a makeshift bookmark that reads &lt;em&gt;New York, NY - Penn Station to Wilmington, DE&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tracks that carry those trains to Wilmington press farther south, arriving later in Washington D.C. and Baltimore. They run through the university town where I spent four years in the early 2000s. And one of their arteries branches farther down the state until it passes my parents&#39; hundred-year-old farm house so closely that the vibrations from the track gently rattle the decorative, wrought iron window on the opposite wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those passing freight trains were an ever-present part of my childhood. Their horns announcing themselves several times each day of my early life. I have crossed those tracks on foot, scooter, bicycle, or car, conservatively, thousands of times. I can feel their smooth, rounded steel under my sneaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those tracks that, decades before I knew them, had once carried passenger rail service rather than coal and stone. The nearby town&amp;rsquo;s train station (now a museum) functioned as a hub, allowing riders to head further east toward the beach or continue south, down the peninsula, toward a little sliver of Virginia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And some of those passengers, surely, were headed north, toward Wilmington. Toward New York City. Passengers who might have seen an earlier version of my second-floor bedroom window as they rolled through southern Delaware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bedroom that I left to go north, toward Wilmington. Toward New York City. The bedroom that I can still find by following a particular set of train tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>0004</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 12:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0004/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a train line that crosses the Delaware River, running along the edges of the Benjamin Franklin Bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the east bank of the river, eastbound trains descend underground before eventually reemerging and climbing onto elevated tracks that carry commuters through the small towns that dot the increasingly suburban landscape of southern New Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From one of those small, drowsy towns, those trains can be heard clearly as they pass. The whine of the electric motors and the rush of the passenger cars cutting through the air makes a    repetitive, comforting addition to the acoustic rhythm of the place. The train sounds like the town. The town sounds like the train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High above this town, which lies just a few miles northeast of the Philadelphia International Airport, there is a particularly busy strip of troposphere. The planes flying overhead are sometimes low enough to make their own contribution to the soundscape, with their softer, slower hum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On clear nights, the methodical blinking lights that announce those planes creep across the dark sky, past the faint stars and the distant Philadelphia skyline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And on clear days, the afternoon sunlight sometimes reflects so perfectly off of those aircraft that their outline appears carved from the blue of the sky itself. The body of a plane, shimmering in the warm sun and the underside of the wings, a deep black. It pulls a shadow behind it that will cross those train tracks, leave that small town, and float over the river, in want of no bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>0003</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0003/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 12:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A charred piece of wood, cracked and decomposing, sat for months in a slowly rusting fire pit on a concrete slab in a small back yard. It sat there through summer heat and rainstorms. It sat there through the cooler fall days and into this winter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This small, square fire pit collected the water from those summer storms. It collected leaves, dropped from an oak tree in a neighbor&amp;rsquo;s yard, branches outstretched over a wooden fence. The leaves dried and broke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It collected the season&amp;rsquo;s first snow on an overcast day in December. That snow melted in the low, warm sun a few days later. Its water dripped though the metal mesh, blending with ease into the cold pool below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That water, the leaves, and the charred piece of wood remained, undisturbed, until a sunny day just before the new year. And when the heavy, screen lid was removed from that small fire pit, it revealed a soft, damp, thick carpet of unexpectedly bright green moss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The piece of wood and the moss now sit, without complaint, in a window box hanging off of a small shed in that small yard. The only of bit green in an already long, grey winter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>0002</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0002/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 12:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a building in center city Philadelphia, made of glass and steel, perched over the east bank of the Schuykill River with a large, open courtyard at its base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This courtyard, a seemingly-public space, expands past the building itself and sprawls out an entire city block. In the warm days of summer, the pavement is thick with the remains of spotted lantern flies that met their violent ends under the sneakers of frustrated Philadelphians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the north and south sides of the building offer stairways, winding up into the air until they meet at opposite ends of a second courtyard, this one with views of the water and a steady, cool breeze. There are picnic tables, benches, shrubs, small trees, flowering vines climbing on wire lattices, and even more open space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open space that, in any city, can be hard to find. Open space that gave my daughter enough room to ride her bicycle for the first time, gliding down what, to a 3-year-old, must have seemed like an absolutely endless car-free corridor of smooth concrete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open space that gives way to the South Street bridge on its north end. A bridge that crosses over the river toward the western edges of the city. A bridge that, before crossing, splits into a ramp that descends toward a boardwalk, running along that river, leading north until it winds inland just enough to branch off again. This time, reversing back up another ramp onto a pedestrian walkway that overlooks a crowded dog run and a pair of basketball courts that my infant son spent hours watching on summer evenings, joyfully yelling some barely intelligible version of the word &lt;em&gt;basketball&lt;/em&gt;, over and over, at strangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end of that walkway settles into the middle of Schuykill River Park. A park that, with its open lawn, well-maintained playground, expansive community garden, and narrow walkways, can seem both empty and crowded at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, before that, just after the ramp rises from the boardwalk, there is a place that, on humid summer mornings offers a tiny, perfect retreat from the weather. This place, close enough to the water to feel its cool air and watch the barges inch past, is thoughtfully hidden from the sun and tucked into the narrow shadow of another building, made of glass and steel, that cuts into the grey-blue sky and glows yellow in the early light.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>0001</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0001/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, while I was tidying up a large plant pot full of garden miscellany, I happened upon a small, empty paper envelope. Or, what I initially thought to be a small, empty paper envelope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it had actually been empty, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been sitting in that large, metal plant pot in that small shed in southern New Jersey. It probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have. It would have been, after being tossed into a recycling can in an unremarkable, midwestern city, carted up to the regional paper recycling plant in St. Paul, Minnesota. The envelope would no longer exist. It would have been transformed into something else. Maybe a sheet of paper or maybe something more interesting like an egg carton sitting in a grocery cooler or a thrilling page of a paperback novel tucked into a nondescript shelf in some quiet bookstore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, no, this paper envelope was not empty when I happened upon it a few days ago. It contained a small quantity of sweet Thai basil seeds. Not a handful, not even a spoonful or a thimbleful. A dozen at best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeds, which a few years earlier, had been purchased from a small company in Fairfield, Maine. Seeds that were packed into this small paper envelope, placed inside of a larger envelope, and then mailed to a three-bedroom apartment in that small, midwestern city. Seeds that followed my family and I last fall when we moved to a narrow, brick row home in southwest Philadelphia. Seeds that joined us again this year when we moved to a slightly wider house across the Delaware River. Seeds that up until a few days ago were lying dormant in that small, nearly empty paper envelope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeds, years old and mostly forgotten, which after a few days of rest in their new bed of dark, brown soil, have erupted into a tiny, delicate forest of future &lt;em&gt;pad krapow&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeds, which were seeds and are now plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plants that spend their lives under a purple-hued grow light, in a white, ceramic pot, in between some (non-Thai) sweet basil and two small Asia Ip shiso plants. Plants which will grow taller and more fragrant each day. Plants which will, with luck, outgrow their new home and someday retire to the small garden that stretches along the wooden fence on the north edge of a backyard where they can, finally, breath fresh air and feel the rain on their leaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small, empty paper envelope, its work done, now sits in a recycling can in our kitchen. It awaits its new life, wondering what it might become.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>01 Coney Island</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Fuji X100S</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Tree</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Sunnyside</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Garden Path</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Trees</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Teak Palace</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>08 Pagoda</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>09 Souel Airport</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Orchids</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>11 Jaws</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Candle</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>13 Street Fog</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>14 View</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>15 Hotel Edison</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>16 Pepsi</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>17 Flowers Window</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>18 Park Chair</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>19 Street Light</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>20 Chrysler</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>21 Flatiron</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>22 Empire State</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>23 Hudson</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>24 Clock</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>25 Steps</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>26 Flower</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>27 Underneath</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>28 Blurred Buddha</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>29 Computer</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>30 Phone</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>31 Platform</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>32 Arch</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>33 Fixture</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>34 Coney Island Beach</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>35 Poets</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>36 Stories</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>37 State House</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>38 Sun Skyline</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>39 Wonder Wheel</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>40 Pencil Black White</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>41 Pencil Color</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>42 City Hall</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>43 Locust</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>44 Subway</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>45 Jar</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>52 Church Windows</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>52 Dark Skyline</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>52 Pillars and Pagodas</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>52 Sunset Philadelphia</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>52 Tomatoes</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2014 10:14:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>