<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes/2016 on Matthew Howell</title>
    <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2016/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes/2016 on Matthew Howell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 11:20:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    

    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Collecting Music</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2022/on-collecting-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 08:17:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2022/on-collecting-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, I spent $11.72 to purchase a CD and have it mailed to my house. Here, I&amp;rsquo;m writing down some thoughts on why I collect music and why, in 2022, I still buy CDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start, three verifiable facts about myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enjoy music. I &lt;em&gt;find joy in music&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have small children and want to share music with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I live a privileged life that includes a bit of disposable time and income, which I can use to do things like collect music and write about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ok-but-why-buy-music&#34;&gt;Ok, but why &lt;em&gt;buy&lt;/em&gt; music?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, we could stream it. Our family shares an Apple Music subscription and it&amp;rsquo;s fine. But, purchasing a physical CD helps me accomplish three things that streaming music does not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-to-support-the-artist&#34;&gt;1. To Support the Artist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying a physical copy of music is an effective and straightforward way to support a musician.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are not always simple ways to support creative work, but buying it is usually a good bet. With direct economic support, we can reward artists for making the art that we love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money for joy, seems a fair transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The economics of streaming services are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-features/streaming-platforms-keeping-more-money-from-artists-than-ever-817925/&#34;&gt;not as clear&lt;/a&gt;. They may be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/22/technology/streaming-music-economics.html&#34;&gt;good for the music industry&lt;/a&gt;, are probably &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/07/arts/music/streaming-music-payments.html&#34;&gt;not great for individual artists&lt;/a&gt;, and seem especially &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/askjack/2019/oct/31/best-streaming-service-mp3-pays-artists&#34;&gt;bad for artists with smaller followings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tiny thoughts on streaming:&lt;/strong&gt;
Streaming music subscriptions are wonderful for discovering music and for making it portable and convenient. I found an appreciation for subscription music after I stopped viewing it as an alternative to collecting, but as a complementary tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stream first and widely, collect sparingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-to-own-the-music&#34;&gt;2. To Own the Music&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably obvious that we do not &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; the music that we stream from Spotify, Apple Music, or wherever else. Cancel that subscription and watch the music evaporate from your phones and devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s not as obvious, is that we don&amp;rsquo;t own the music that we &lt;em&gt;purchase&lt;/em&gt; digitally, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purchasing and owning a digital good is precarious, at best. Often, as consumers, we make these purchases that would be better described as complex licensing agreements that can be ended, unilaterally, by the licenser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Examples of poor behavior involving digital purchases:&lt;/strong&gt;
Amazon can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.engadget.com/2009-10-01-amazon-clarifies-kindle-book-deletion-policy-can-still-delete-b.html&#34;&gt;remove &amp;ldquo;your books&amp;rdquo; from &amp;ldquo;your Kindle,&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; Google Play Music &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2020/08/05/google-play-music-to-shut-down-starting-in-september-will-disappear-by-december/&#34;&gt;no longer allows downloads of &amp;ldquo;your music,&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/wirecutter/blog/you-dont-own-your-digital-movies/&#34;&gt;you never really owned &amp;ldquo;your movies&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; from Vudu. All of these large companies &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sony.com/electronics/support/articles/00070056&#34;&gt;routinely&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2019/4/2/18292177/microsoft-ebooks-refund-stops-selling-digital-books-store&#34;&gt;lose&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2017/10/02/microsoft-will-soon-shutter-its-music-store-and-streaming-service-move-users-to-spotify/&#34;&gt;interest&lt;/a&gt; in selling digital goods or supporting the ones they&amp;rsquo;ve already sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our shared understanding of &lt;em&gt;ownership&lt;/em&gt; just doesn&amp;rsquo;t transfer honestly to digital purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For certain records, I want more than that conditional, temporary access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owning a physical copy of music provides privileges that streaming does not. I can listen to a CD indefinitely, with no Internet connection, and without a monthly cost. I can make a copy of it. I can sell it. I can donate it. My children can inherit it, have a quick laugh, and then donate it themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;For the records that bring me joy, I want to live with them, find them space on our shelf, and share them with my family.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-to-collect-artifacts&#34;&gt;3. To Collect Artifacts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, owning a physical piece of music is fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can hold an object in my hand that was made by another person. There is an emotional heft to that connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the simple, tactile ritual of opening the digipak, removing the disc, placing it on the tray, watching it disappear into the machine, hearing the mechanical whirl of motor, and waiting for the laser to assemble the song from the landscape of the plastic and push it through the speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How CDs work, kind of:&lt;/strong&gt;
CDs are made by encoding music into digital data and physically pressing that data into the plastic disc. The data is arranged in a single line that begins in the center of the disc and spirals out toward the edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To play the music back, the disc is rotated and those indentations (called &lt;em&gt;pits&lt;/em&gt;) are read by a laser and a lens to reconstruct the original data. That data is then handed it off to a DAC (digital-to-analog converter), which converts it to an analogue waveform, which is sent to an amplifier, and finally to a speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music becomes data written onto a disc, the data is read back and becomes the music again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compact_disc&#34;&gt;Read a lot more at Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this physical experience is easily shared with my children. They regard CDs with wonder and interest that aren&amp;rsquo;t present when they&amp;rsquo;re poking at shapes on a screen. &lt;mark&gt;Humans understand physical objects.&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-not-vinyl&#34;&gt;Why not vinyl?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The large, round elephant in the room at this point is: why not collect vinyl records?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago when I decided to return to CDs, I did spend some time considering vinyl. Below is my personal reasoning for choosing CDs and not an argument &lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; vinyl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, I am happy that vinyl is finding more popularity in recent years. Yay for supporting artists, owning music, collecting artifacts, and having choices!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-vinyl-records-are-less-robust-than-cds&#34;&gt;1. Vinyl records are less robust than CDs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vinyl records require more care and more careful handling, which just isn&amp;rsquo;t possible to explain to my 3-year-old son. For us, &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.discogs.com/en/how-to-store-vinyl-records/&#34;&gt;taking care of vinyl&lt;/a&gt; doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like a good use of our energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-cd-production-is-more-reliable&#34;&gt;2. CD production is more reliable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read enough reviews of vinyl records online and you will find more than a few complaints about the &amp;ldquo;pressing.&amp;rdquo; The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yoursoundmatters.com/watch-out-for-these-faults-when-buying-new-vinyl-records/&#34;&gt;vinyl manufacturing process seems prone to inconsistency&lt;/a&gt; that isn&amp;rsquo;t as common with CDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-cds-are-cheaper-than-vinyl&#34;&gt;3. CDs are cheaper than vinyl&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just paid $11.72 for a brand new CD and used CDs are easy to find and cheaper still. Most new vinyl records go for $20 to $25 and are often priced even higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This price difference amplifies concerns about the robustness and reliability of vinyl. It also illustrates the  clear value of the next point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-cds-are-user-replaceable&#34;&gt;4. CDs are user-replaceable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I break or lose a CD, I can produce a new, perfect copy of it in my own home, for very little money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an absolutely beautiful accident of capitalism. CDs are a well-supported, high-quality digital media format that manage to retain a lot of the freedom of simpler analog formats. We were lucky to have this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How CDs happened:&lt;/strong&gt;
Sony and Philips jointly developed the format so that they could sell CD players. Record labels embraced CDs to monetize their back catalogs. Later, personal computers and cheap hardware allowed consumers to pull high-quality music files from purchased discs and then make their own copies and mixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that a new physical music format will be developed. Even if it were, would we ever get another universal format supported by plentiful and cheap hardware, embraced by record labels, and endowed with as much freedom and utility as CDs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More thoughts on this below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-cd-players-are-cheap-and-sound-great&#34;&gt;5. CD players are cheap and sound great&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CD player in our home was purchased a few years ago for less than the cost of a good Bluetooth speaker. It has AM and FM tuners, Bluetooth, analog input and output, and two very nice stereo speaker boxes made of real wood. It also has a large volume dial, clicky buttons for most functions, and even came with a remote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A comparable quality record player, with an amp, and a pair of bookshelf speakers would almost certainly cost quite a bit more. And it might, on occasion, need a new stylus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-cds-are-smaller&#34;&gt;6. CDs are smaller&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CDs take up less space on the shelf, and they&amp;rsquo;re easier for young children to handle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-cds-offer-instant-seeking-and-other-song-navigation-features&#34;&gt;7. CDs offer instant seeking and other song navigation features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a big deal when CDs were released and positioned as an improvement on cassette tapes. No more fast-forwarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, kids love to put songs on repeat. Just try to stop them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-vinyl&#34;&gt;Why vinyl?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vinyl is popular and it&amp;rsquo;s not without reason. For folks choosing it, a few points stand out to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That big, beautiful, best-in-class album art&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The undeniable romance of placing the record on the turntable and carefully dropping the arm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That warm, weathered sound profile that many people just prefer over digital music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some folks enjoy the experience of only listening to entire albums, no skips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;also-maybe-cassettes&#34;&gt;Also, maybe cassettes!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cassette tapes are also, oddly, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inquirer.com/entertainment/music/cassette-tape-revival-philadelphia-music-20210321.html&#34;&gt;available again&lt;/a&gt; from a lot of independent sellers, often as a limited run or special release. This strikes me as mostly nostalgia?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, cassettes did have some nice characteristics. They are smaller and more portable than CDs. Mixtapes were really fun. And golly, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2014/7/1/5861062/sony-walkman-at-35&#34;&gt;that Sony Walkman was an iconic piece of design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-ideal-format&#34;&gt;An Ideal Format&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy to have CDs, and they fit my needs well, but they are surely not perfect. My ideal music format might be something like a large, ultra-durable SD card. An unbreakable, game cartridge-sized music whatsit that can be packaged alongside album art and other niceties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great, modern physical music format might have these attributes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lossless music encoding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robust and durable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small and portable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unencrypted and accessible data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to copy, reproduce, and make your own&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attractive and beautiful as an object&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No reliance on the Internet or a cloud service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait. Am I just describing &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MiniDisc&#34;&gt;Sony MiniDisc&lt;/a&gt;? Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m sad that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2013/2/15/3989872/status-symbols-sony-minidisc&#34;&gt;MiniDisc never found its market&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, I am sad about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some folks working on things like this, but nothing that I found looked very promising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are some neat DIY projects using a Raspberry Pi and an NFC reader. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.com/news/who-needs-vinyl-records-when-youve-got-raspberry-pi-and-nfc/&#34;&gt;This one&lt;/a&gt; looks nice. But, a DIY solution isn&amp;rsquo;t accessible to very many people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitaltrends.com/home-theater/senic-muse-blocks-nfc-custom-printed-music-shortcuts/&#34;&gt;Muse Blocks&lt;/a&gt; are NFC music cards that look nice, but they&amp;rsquo;re just a link to streaming services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sharetapes.com/&#34;&gt;Sharetapes&lt;/a&gt;, also, look like an NFC card that links to streaming services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://access.trackrhino.com/make-music-physical-again&#34;&gt;TrackRhino&lt;/a&gt; is an NFC card and maybe allows music file downloads, but it&amp;rsquo;s linked to a cloud service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://usbmusiccards.com&#34;&gt;USB Music Cards&lt;/a&gt; (which really need a better name) look OK, but they&amp;rsquo;re selling an analytics product along with it. &amp;ldquo;Know when (day, month, year) and where (City, State, Country) your fans are listening to your music.&amp;rdquo; Yuck and no, thank you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, for the foreseeable future, collecting music means CDs on our shelf.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 in Favorites</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2021/2021-in-favorites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 20:15:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2021/2021-in-favorites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bookshop.org/books/the-memory-police/9781101911815&#34;&gt;The Memory Police&lt;/a&gt; by Yōko Ogawa was &lt;mark&gt;my favorite book&lt;/mark&gt; that I read in 2021. It was originally published in 1994 in Japan, but an English translation (by Stephen Snyder) was released in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this book is a masterpiece. An allegory for fascism? Or Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease? Or maybe just the existential dread of a finite and temporary world? Maybe. It&amp;rsquo;s also about humans taking care of each other in a hopeless situation. Whatever it is, it&amp;rsquo;s beautiful and feels exquisitely crafted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.matthewhowell.net/reading&#34;&gt;everything I read&lt;/a&gt; in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://theweatherstation.bandcamp.com/album/ignorance&#34;&gt;Ignorance by The Weather Station&lt;/a&gt; was &lt;mark&gt;my favorite record&lt;/mark&gt; of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick and incomplete checklist of my musical preferences: driving percussions, piano melodies, lush string arrangements, talented female vocalists who slip into confident falsettos, and former child actresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, check, check, check, check, and check. This record was such a treat to listen to this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For two days, in the middle of the post-vaccine, pre-Delta summer, I decamped to a cabin in the New Jersey pine barrens to refresh four decade-old friendships with some long talks, very light hiking, and a lot of food. This was all orchestrated by my lovely, lovely wife and it was very, very appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was &lt;mark&gt;my favorite and only trip&lt;/mark&gt; of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t write much this year, but I did manage to keep my weekly writing cadence for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text&#34;&gt;Alt Text&lt;/a&gt; going until July. That is… not a terrible result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0002/&#34;&gt;0002 Glass and Steel&lt;/a&gt; (or maybe &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.matthewhowell.net/projects/alt-text/0006/&#34;&gt;0006 Hills&lt;/a&gt;) was &lt;mark&gt;my favorite piece of writing&lt;/mark&gt; of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This photo of the treeline reflecting off the water at Trap Pond State Park is &lt;mark&gt;my favorite photograph&lt;/mark&gt; of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A butterfly flew past at the moment that the shutter opened. The lens gathered just enough light to see the yellow markings on its wings. Most of my photographic success relies on chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full resolution image is available for anyone to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/photos/UWT9whAm_5E&#34;&gt;at Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/_images/matthew-howell-20210504-trap-pond-960.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;The treeline reflecting off the water at Trap Pond State Park. White clouds in the blue sky. A butterfly floats past.&#34; /&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Values</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2016/personal-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 20:06:12 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2016/personal-values/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A publicly accessible and occasionally refined list of personal values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, be kind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be more generous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be honest and clear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be reliable, earn trust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find energy in optimism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Believe in people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>30</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2013/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 08:09:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2013/30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is May, 10th 2013, which means that I am now thirty years old. Thanks to calendars, I saw this coming and was able to prepare myself. I even found some time over the last three decades (!) to write a few words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presented as advice to my younger self, exactly thirty things that I (think I kind of) know:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try not to give unsolicited advice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Showing up on time, consistently and without fanfare, is the single best way to show another person that you respect them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People should hear nice things about themselves. Do not assume that everyone does. Give more honest compliments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you drink beer, drink the absolute best beer available, even if that means you can afford fewer beers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to be the best person that you can be all the time. Maintaining different identities is a burden and it distracts you from working on your real one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kindness, and the strength to display it in all situations, is the single most admirable quality that people can possess.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If given the opportunity, people will surprise you. Leaving yourself open to these surprises is a kind of risk. Taking that risk is how you believe in people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Own fewer things. Identify possessions that you love. Take care of them, treat them well, and keep them forever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When with others, make every possible effort to be with them wholeheartedly and every possible effort to not fiddle with your mobile devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every photograph and video you take at a concert or other live event will probably be terrible. Just enjoy the moments, don&amp;rsquo;t feel pressured to document them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let people leave your life when they need to. Leave a light on for them in case they ever decide to return. Collect those lights and regularly remember why you keep them lit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write more letters. Literal, pen-and-paper, had-to-buy-a-stamp-and-remember-where-your-friend-lives letters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be a relentless champion of people you care about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When hugging, hug with two arms, while standing and applying reasonable, affectionate pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take every possible precaution to ensure that you own what you make: words, art, music, photographs, and even social media updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you make something that you think could help someone, give it away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to bed an hour earlier and wake up an hour earlier. Life is nicer in the morning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give more, smaller, unexpected, personal gifts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You will miss things. You will not live long enough to experience everything. Try to spend time with this in mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To accomplish something difficult, make the work as easy as you can on yourself. Remove every obstacle except the work. Then do the work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When writing lists of advice, simply mine your past mistakes and failures, then try to rephrase them as folksy wisdom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are not many tasks that you&amp;rsquo;ll be doing repeatedly for as long as you&amp;rsquo;re alive, carrying stuff is probably one of them. Buy a really nice bag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other people cannot always see your intentions, they can see your actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No matter how important the rush that you are in, there exists someone in a more important rush, possibly the person directly in front of you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find something small, cheap, and easily reproducible that makes your day better. Make it a point to include it in life as often as possible. I suggest tea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settle into the realization that other people can be as intelligent as you. And more intelligent. And less intelligent. But, understand that you often won&amp;rsquo;t be able to tell the difference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask your parents more questions about themselves, answer more of your parents&#39; questions about yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unless you have finished writing a book, it&amp;rsquo;s probably best not to tell anyone that you are writing a book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seeking comfort is just fine. Seeking unending comfort can be a trap; occasionally, pursue the uncomfortable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Placing a ripe, soft avocado in a refrigerator will extend its life by two days, give or take.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once in a while, when you feel strongly about it, break a rule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shipping is a Habit</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2013/shipping-is-a-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 08:09:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2013/shipping-is-a-habit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing software is an art form. As much as it relies on engineering and science, at its heart, it is a creative pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The programmer, like the poet, works only slightly removed from pure thought-stuff. He builds his castles in the air, from air, creating by the exertion of the imagination.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– Fred Brooks, The Mythical Man Month&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, programming seems to be an art form that lends itself to unfinished work. We build castles in the air, but we rarely allow others to visit. We take comfort in our open projects and their obscurity. Sometimes, it can be more exciting to be working than to have worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, real artists ship and shipping is a conscious decision. Software does not ship itself. No one is going to discover your nearly-finished bug tracker 100 years after your death while buying your MacBook at a yard sale, launch it, and give you credit. Ship it while you&amp;rsquo;re alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get trapped by the idea that our work can be better. That more time and work will inevitably yield better results. Of course this is true, but it will always be true. It will never be finished, but it might already be mostly finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You guys have been working on this stuff for months now, another couple weeks isn&amp;rsquo;t going to make that much of a difference. You may as well get it over with. Just make it as good as you can.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– Steve Jobs, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.folklore.org/StoryView.py?story=Real_Artists_Ship.txt&#34;&gt;Real Artists Ship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, real artists ship. This is not a new idea. What I would like to propose is that &lt;em&gt;shipping is a habit&lt;/em&gt;. Real artists are habitually shipping, they cannot stop shipping, and they understand the value of shipping. Shipping, publishing, putting-private-work-into-the-public-space frees it from the tight grasp of its creator. Art becomes real at the moment that it ships, the moment that a second person sees it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a cycle that refreshes itself. Constructive feedback, or praise, or disagreement are all seeds of creativity&amp;rsquo;s more practical cousin: iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software, like many art forms, is perpetually unfinished. Pushing it out the door is the first step in the iteration process. And iteration is the only path to great work. Second drafts are refinements of first drafts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exposing our efforts into public light is adicting. We start to value our public works more than our private ones, not for their notoriety, but for their temporary completeness. For the idea that they were, in some imperfect moment, finished. We ship to move our work off of the stack, to make room in our minds and our lives for new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Shipping is the collision between your work and the outside world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– Seth Godin, &lt;a href=&#34;http://books.google.com/books?id=dI66B5IY2X0C&amp;amp;pg=PT97&amp;amp;lpg=PT97&amp;amp;dq=godin+linchpin+%22real+artists+ship%22&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=B-nIIK7AG9&amp;amp;sig=XtKx6wpQqXPg8e0FM-0AYJGq1cQ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=qmYET-2wMcXL0QG3ue3iBA&amp;amp;sqi=2&amp;amp;ved=0CB0Q6AEwAA#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;Linchpin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, ship something today. Launch something that is useful, but isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect. Publicize something that you&amp;rsquo;re only half-happy with. Show someone else a part of yourself that you aren&amp;rsquo;t particularly impressed with. The goal should be to return to that work a year later and be amused by its amateurism, for having grown. Or to return to that work tomorrow, driven to improve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much scarier than any result of shipping, is the idea that not shipping can become a habit too. We can be seduced by the comfort of our own minds and our own opinions of the work that we do. Our own feedback is overly accommodating, we are made partial by our own memories of how difficult it can be to create something. We can be scared to invite feedback that isn&amp;rsquo;t colored by the struggle of creation. But, while fear is a poor choice of motivator to stay put, it&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic reason to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are very few acts more human than to make something. And when we &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2012/make-things-and-give-them-to-people/&#34;&gt;share those things with others&lt;/a&gt;, we get to grow in ways that we didn&amp;rsquo;t plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep building your castles in the air, but get in the habit of publishing the address.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tins, Watches, and Emotional Assignments</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2012/tins-watches-and-emotional-assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 08:09:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2012/tins-watches-and-emotional-assignments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the bookcase above my desk, surrounded by a dust ring of neglect, rests an old, oval, tin box that once belonged to my great grandfather. It&amp;rsquo;s weathered with a beautiful patina that nearly obscures the detailed scenes etched into it, but just manages to make it look lived-in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a single business card in that tin. The card is simple in its design, but thorough in its description of his job: &amp;ldquo;Master and Pilot for Yachts for the Atlantic Coast and Inland Waters from Maine to Florida.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a title! Sixteen words. The phone number listed on the card is a mere three digits. His first and middle name are described only in initials. Delaware is abbreviated to Del. But, that title is there fully in all of its ridiculous specificity. He must have been a proud Master and Pilot for Yachts for the Atlantic Coast and Inland Waters from Maine to Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are very few things that I own which carry any emotional or sentimental weight to them.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Manufactured goods are sterile in that way. So, it&amp;rsquo;s much easier to develop an affection for older items. It&amp;rsquo;s easier to believe they&amp;rsquo;ve had a life. Indifference is for things and emotions are for people. Or sometimes really, really old things that once belonged to people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On occasion, I think it&amp;rsquo;s useful to deliberately assign some value to those things that we choose to let surround us. By doing so, we can take an object and make it more. We can make it our own. We can give it a life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day, I wear my Casio A168. Right now, it tells me that the time is 21:08. It lights up a stunning teal from the 1980&amp;rsquo;s and it keeps track of leap years effortlessly. It is simple, it is ugly, and you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000GB0FXU/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=matthowe-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000GB0FXU&#34;&gt;buy one for about 14 bucks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Etched into the back of this mass-produced work of art are some mass-produced words. CASIO. STAINLESS STEEL BACK. WATER RESISTANT. Made in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fair enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than those words will ever convey, this little thing has been perched on my wrist for some wonderful moments of my life. I saw my sister get married in this watch. It, literally, touched my nephew the very first time that I held him. It moved to New York City with me. I once fell in love wearing it. It is the subject of the most thoughtful gift that I have ever received. And as I wrote each of these words it was with me, encouraging me from my left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have stretched my arm past my sleeve, letting it poke out to tell me the hour, literally, hundreds of times. It intimately knows every shirt that I own. It keeps track of any changes in the circumference of my wrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a personal logo, a brand, and a mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a watch, but I have high hopes for its life. It will inevitably outlive me. I hope that it finds its way to a great, great grandchild of mine. And if it ever gets that far, I for damn sure better have etched even more memories into it.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; And so, it and I keep going. We keep making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a watch. But, I&amp;rsquo;ve assigned it a larger role than that. It is a flag pole, clasped to my wrist, reminding me of the time, my age, and moments in my life that I am lucky enough to want to remember. With &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electroluminescence&#34;&gt;electroluminescence&lt;/a&gt; in case they happen at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an apartment-building-fire situation, this tin is one of a small handful of items that I would grab before tumbling down my fire escape to the safety.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I should probably provide a few decade&amp;rsquo;s worth of (currently) available batteries.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Things and Give Them to People</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2012/make-things-and-give-them-to-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2012 08:09:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2012/make-things-and-give-them-to-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2002 Kurt Vonnegut gave a speech in southern Michigan to the graduating class of Albion College. Most of what he said that day ended up being included in his memoir, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/158322713X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=matthowe-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=158322713X&#34;&gt;A Man Without A Country&lt;/a&gt;, which I absolutely recommend reading. But, I&amp;rsquo;m going to pull out two phrases and one point which I think he crafted just beautifully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indulge me and jump to about the 5:55 mark in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ESwSiKRs9hc&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; and stick around for two minutes or so. He&amp;rsquo;ll start off with a joke, but it will build the context for the two quotes that I&amp;rsquo;ll pull below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many people think that practicing an art is a way to make a living, is a good way to make a living. Practicing an art, no matter how well or badly, is a way to make your soul grow, for heaven&amp;rsquo;s sake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He then gives the audience a homework assignment. He asks them to write a poem, as best they can, show it to no one and then destroy it. And here&amp;rsquo;s what he expects will happen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you will find out, you have been rewarded, big time. This came out of you! This is the act of creativity. The hell with fame, the hell with money, you created this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking a little closer and using the VTPE&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; we can come to the conclusion that Kurt was leading us to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
if art = soul growth
and making things = art
then making things = soul growth
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of different ways that we can spend our time and I won&amp;rsquo;t be declaring that I understand life well enough to tell anyone how to spend theirs. But, I will write that I do not believe Kurt was wrong here. You will not be disappointed in spending a few minutes, or even a few hours, making something. The reward that we get, as human beings, from &lt;strong&gt;making things&lt;/strong&gt; is undeniable and universal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best argument that I can grasp to support that universality is how much creating we all do as children. When unencumbered and encouraged, we were creating-machines. We colored any wax-able surface and constructed forts on anything fort-bearing. But, for so many of us, this making slows down as we age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a simple, two-step plan to remedy that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make things again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give them to people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second step incentivizes the first. Our organic desire to create may wane over the years, but in that same time our connections to people have grown. We&amp;rsquo;ve figured out, in own ways, what friendship is, and what respect is, and what love is. And with those books on our shelves, unfinished as they may always be, we can make fantastic things.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, after making something, if you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable with it (and sometimes even if you&amp;rsquo;re not), &lt;strong&gt;give it to someone&lt;/strong&gt;. Because, as human as making things is, its humanity pales next to making things for another person. Giving a gift is another, perfectly wonderful way to make your soul grow. So, here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m positing as an addendum to Kurt&amp;rsquo;s proof:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
if making things = soul growth
and giving things to people = soul growth
then making things and giving them to people = soul growth x 2
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s two times the soul growth for the &lt;strong&gt;maker-giver&lt;/strong&gt;. Plus, the net soul gain for the &lt;strong&gt;receiver&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write someone something, draw someone something, or sing someone something. Make anyone anything. But, sometimes, give it to them. Choose the something and the someone appropriately or inappropriately. Choose so that it&amp;rsquo;s easy, or that it&amp;rsquo;s hard, or that it&amp;rsquo;s unexpected.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; You will get a reward from both the making and the giving. You will get to give a brand new part of yourself that is distinct and that was made just for another person. You will get to be reminded that you can still make new parts of yourself. All of that will be inside this &lt;strong&gt;thing that you made.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, make things and give them to people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s twice the soul growth. At least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vonnegut Transitive Property of Equality&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i1iiiEgqgT4&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://pauloctavious.com/bookcollection&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zefrank.com/chillout&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/handwritten/id452771113&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t really tried to quantify this, but it&amp;rsquo;s almost certainly positive.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s my personal favorite.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ties</title>
      <link>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2012/ties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 08:09:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.matthewhowell.net/notes/2012/ties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was 12 years old, my father taught me to tie a four-in-hand knot. He gave me a hands-on lesson and a sheet of illustrated instructions from an old tie box. We disagreed on the ideal width of that knot, a preference which evidently increases with one&amp;rsquo;s years, but we both understood the utility of it. It was simple. And it served a purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also understood that I was, from that moment on, the tier of my own ties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That four-in-hand has accompanied me to interviews, to weddings, and to funerals. It&amp;rsquo;s come with me to new cities and returned with me to old towns. It&amp;rsquo;s shown up for important moments in my life and helped me show up, appropriately dressed, for important moments in the lives of people close to me. And sixteen years later, I am still recreating it, crudely, each morning before I before I go to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write software for a living in a windowless basement. The dress code for which is not formal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have not found that women are unavoidably attracted to neckwear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That tie gets to leave my closet every weekday, and gets to ride on a train or a bicycle, to serve as a reminder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spend a non-trivial amount of my time trying to improve and to update skills that I am lucky enough to be able to earn a living with. Those skills allow me to make things. They allow me to call home a city that I love. And they help me to define a curiosity which I feel grateful to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I aspire to that same effort in the parts of my life for which I am not paid. I want to be better in what I write, and in what I say, and in how I treat people. I have days when I am so aware of all of this that it&amp;rsquo;s thick in the air the moment that I wake up. But, I have days when it&amp;rsquo;s not. And it&amp;rsquo;s useful to build a symbol of it into my routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That tie allows me to literally affix my aspirations to my neck with a knot. It is simple. And it serves a purpose. I put it on in the morning and it becomes a small, sometimes striped reminder that I am going to be a professional today, in everything that I do. And that I am on my own to tie the knot and to choose the width.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>